Grégoire JEANMART

Software Engineer

PERSONAL STATEMENT

French expatriate in London since 2016, I'm currently Head of Innovation for Ai-London, a software vendor specialized in Insurance Policy Administration System. I'm responsible of architecture, methodology and framework development.

During the last year, I developed an important enthusiasm in Blockchain and decentralized technologies such as Ethereum and Bitcoin. I learned theory and practice on my spare time but now I would like to be part of this disruption with new professional opportunities in London.

KEY SKILLS

- Problem solver
- o Fast learner
- > Passionate and polyglot programmer
- Blockchain enthusiastic

INFORMATION

Age 29 (21/12/1987)

Nationality French

Languages

o French: mother tongue

o English: professional proficiency

o Spanish: beginner

Interest & activities

- o Music: drums (15 years) and guitar (5 years)
- o Movies TV Shows
- o Travelling and discovering many cultures
- o Dog lover

Driving License and First-aid certificate

CONTACT

@ gregoire.jeanmart@gmail.com

s gregoire.jeanmart

+44 (0)7 761 866 262 gjeanmart.github.io

linkedin.com/in/gjeanmart

🕠 github.com/gjeanmart

gjeanmart

twitter.com/GregJeanmart

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Head of Innovation at Ai-London

From Jan. 2017 to present in London (UK)



This position is the opportunity to explore new technical areas relevant for the Insurance & Financial industry and for our platform. I make research on technologies such as Big Data, Machine Learning, Blockchain, etc.

My works consists in working on prototypes integrated with our solution; assist the CTO in the architectural choices and team management; and participate to the sale process. I also provide expertise on our technological stack for new features, bug fixes and support.

> Head of Middleware at Ai-London

From Jan. 2016 to Dec. 2016 in London (UK)

Responsible of the Middleware layer for an Insurance Policy Administration system covering the entire policy lifecycle (quote, application, policy maintenance, claim, maturity) using Java/JavaScript solution.

Involve in architecture, design, development, test and documentation of the Web API (SOAP and REST).

Software Engineer and Junior Manager at RS2i



From Aug. 2011 to Nov. 2015 in Paris (France)

RS2i gave me the opportunity to learn and understand the principles of complex Information Technologies System in very different domains and technologies.

- o **Middleware architect and developer** for Enterprise business solutions (ESB, BPM, MDM) using Java J2EE and TIBCO technologies.
- o **Junior IT project manager:** Planning, cost, writing functional/technical specifications, automation, packaging, define business needs and manage resources (agile methods).

> Software engineer intern at RS2i

From Feb. 2011 to Aug. 2011 in Paris (France)

Post-graduated internship. Responsible of a technical study for a BPM engine and development of a J2EE framework to simplify the integration and speed up the development.

➤ Web engineer intern at NDS Technologies



From June 2009 to Feb. 2010 in Issy-Les-Moulineaux (France)

Design of web 2.0 widgets (Twitter, Yahoo Weather/Stocks, Flickr, Facebook, Ebay ...) for TV using an embedded web browser

EDUCATION

> UTT : Université de Technologie de Troyes



2008–2011 in Troyes (France)

Master of Science in Information Technologies engineering Specialization: *Software Project Management*

> UTT : Université de Technologie de Troyes

2006-2008 in Troyes (France)

Two-year science foundation courses: mathematics, physics, chemistry

Baccalaureate S (French A levels) with merit

2006 in Cherbourg (France)

Specialties: Engineering Sciences & Mathematics

PROJECTS & MISSIONS



Ai-PAS for Ai-London

From Jan 2016 to Present in London (UK)

Ai-PAS is a system of records developed for Insurance policies that supports the entire policy lifecycle from quote to maturity.

Responsibilities

- o Research & Development
- Architecture and Design
- Development and documentation

Technical details

- o Solution: 3-tier architecture, SaaS, Mobile
- Languages, technologies and tools:
 - FrontEnd: JavaScript, AngularJS
 - Middleware: Java8, Spring, Maven, Keycloak, Alfresco, Jaspersoft, Stripe
 - Backend: Oracle 12c, Oracle PL/SQL
- Infrastructure: AWS, Linux



Best DApp for Education: MyTutor - Status Hackaton

In June 2017

Status is an Ethereum mobile gateway that provides a browser for decentralized Application (DApp) and a messaging solution. In June 2017, Status runs a one-week virtual hackaton where participants built status compatible DApp or chatbot.

Project description

MyTutor is a DApp that brings teachers/tutors and students closer without any intermediaries. It's an assistant that allows teacher to publish an ad, the student can look over the ads and start chatting with a teacher, after Q&A and agreeing a date, time and a price, the teacher can setup a course. The student has to make a payment into the contract before the course starts. Once the course is finished, the teacher can either release the payment to his account or refund.

Technical details

- Backend: Solidity & Truffle
- Frontend: JavaScript/Typescript, Ionic2 and Angular2



ESB & SOA Consultant at SNCF

From June 2013 to March 2015 in Paris (France)

SNCF is France's national state-owned railway company and manages the rail traffic in France.

Responsibilities:

In the context of the development of many BPM and SOA projects for SNCF. I was TIBCO technologies expert consultant (BusinessWorks, EMS, AMX and Spotfire) accompanying internal and external IT teams in their project processes. I oversaw:

- o Design of high performance and high availability software 10 million msg / day
- o Design pattern definition
- Programmer's training

Details:

- o Solutions: EAI/ESB, MDM, SOA
- o Languages, technologies and tools: Java J2EE, Shell, JSON, TIBCO (BusinessWorks, EMS, Administrator, Hawk, Spotfire), Oracle DB & APEX, Continuous integration
- o Infrastructure: VMWare, RedHat, Windows Server

OTHER PROFESSIONAL REFERENCES



TOTAL [Industry]

BPM/SOA Tech Lead in Paris From Jun. 2011 to Nov. 2015



AXA [Insurance]

J2EE developer in Brussels *From May* 2012 *to Sept.* 2012



SONEPAR [Industry]

MDM/SOA consultant in Paris From Oct. 2013 to Mar. 2014



LCL [Bank]

BPM consultant in Paris From Dec 2014 to Mar. 2015

t'Argus de la presse

Argus de la Presse [Media] Project Manager in Paris

From Dec. 2012 to Nov. 2015

DETAILLED SKILLS

Software engineering

- Design, development, testing, documentation
- Architecture (Middleware: SOA/ESB, API, Micro-services, Databases)
- o Project Management
- o Infrastructure, Cloud/SaaS
- o Continuous Integration/Deployment

Programming

С

С

С

С

0

C

Java (8)	
JavaScript (es6)	南南南南南
SQL	南南南南京
HTML	***
CSS	南南南流流
Shell	***
PHP	***
Python	***
Solidity	चे से से से के
Typescript	***

Frameworks, Tools & Databases

o J2EE Spring	*	÷	÷	÷	÷
o J2EE Hibernate	+	÷		÷	
o JS AngularJS (v1)	+	÷	÷		÷
o JS AngularJS (v2)	+	÷	÷	ě	÷
o Git	W	ŵ	Ŕ	ŵ	ŵ
o Maven	育	育	À	À	Ŕ
o Jenkins	+	÷	÷	÷	ŵ
o NodeJS - npm				-8-	
o TIBCO suites	*	Ť	i	À	Ŕ
o SQL (Oracle, PostGre, MySQL)	*	÷	÷	÷	ŵ
o NoSQL (MongoDB, ELK)					
o Truffle + Web3					-

OS & IaaS

o Linux	***
o Windows Server	
o VMWare	
o AWS	***
$\circ \ Google Cloud Platform \$	888 8 8 8